Florence Rena Sabin Papers, 1872-1985
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES IV. PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES 1911-1952
  - Clubs
    - Colonial Dames, 1931-44, undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Colorado State Federation of Business and Professional Women's Clubs, 1945, undated (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Cosmopolitan Club, 1926-51, undated (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous, 1932-40 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Colorado Committee for Resource Development, 1947-52, undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Colorado Public Health Association, 1941-48 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Colorado State Department of Public Health
    - Hospital survey
      - Miscellaneous correspondence, reports, and printed material, 1942-47, undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Tabulation of Hospital Inventory Data, 1947 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Polio report, 1946-51, undated (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Dairy products, 1944-47, undated (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous, 1932-47, undated (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Colorado State Civil Service Commission, 1945-46 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Colorado State Medical Society, 1944-47, undated (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Colorado State Planning Commission, 1945 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Colorado Tuberculosis Association
    - Committee minutes and agenda, 1946-47 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence and reports, 1937-52, undated (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Denver Department of Health and Hospitals, 1951-54, undated (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Denver Tuberculosis Association, 1945-52, undated (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Finney Howell Research Foundation, 1938-50, undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Governor's Legislative Committee on Stream Pollution, 1951-52, undated (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Governor's Post War Planning Committee
    [See also SERIES VI. PHOTOGRAPHS AND MEMORABILIA-- Photographs]
    - Buck Reports, 1945-50 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1944-47 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Reports, minutes, notes, statistics
      - Contents of Sabin's notebook, 1946, undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - 1944-49 (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - undated (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - State Health Committee, 1947 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Henry Strong Denison Memorial Foundation, 1935-49, undated (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Foundation (Box 23)
    [See SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE--Friends and associates- Henry Allen Moe]
  - Johns Hopkins Women Medical Alumnae Association, 1922-44, undated (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Joint Committee for the Study of Medical Care for the Indigent, 1952-53 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - National Committee on Improvement of Nursing Services, 1945-51, undated (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - National Health Assembly, 1948
    - Correspondence (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Section on State and Community Planning For Health (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - National Research Council, 1945-47, undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - National Tuberculosis Association
    - Bulletins, 1939-53 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1938-47 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Committee on Medical Research: reports, minutes, agenda
      - 1939-44 (Box 24, Folder 7-9)
      - 1945-48 (Box 25, Folder 1-5)
    - Trudeau Medal Committee, 1945-48 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous reports and printed material, 1939-52 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - New York Academy of Sciences, Section on Biology, Conference on "LYMPH," 1945 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - New York University Hall of Fame
    - Correspondence and notes, 1935-45, undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Printed material, 1939-45 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research, 1938-49 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - United China Relief, 1941, undated (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - U.S. Department of State, 1944-45 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - U.S. Public Health Service
    - Correspondence, 1945-49 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Division of Hospital Facilities, Conference, 1947 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - University of Denver, Social Science Foundation, Conference on Atomic Energy, 1945 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - World Center for Women's Archives, 1936-38, undated (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous, 1911-52, undated (Box 27, Folder 6-7)
- SERIES V. SUBJECTS 1929-58
  - American Institute of Biology, undated (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Bang's Disease, 1946-47 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    [See also SERIES IV. PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES--Governor's Post War Planning Committee--State Health Committee]
  - Epidemics, 1939-41, undated (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Foreign Policy Association, 1933-38 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Gates, Frederick Taylor, 1929 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Gaub, W.H., 1945-46 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Gibbs, Edna Leonhardt, 1958 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Hospitals, 1942-47, undated (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Kauver, C.E. H., 1952 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Legislation and bills, 1937-53, undated (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Smith College, 1927-55 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Vermont Academy, 1939-51 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Women in Medicine, 1939 (Box 28, Folder 13)
- SERIES VI. PHOTOGRAPHS AND MEMORABILIA 1893-1954
  - Photographs
    - Florence Rena Sabin
      - Early photos, undated (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - Smith College, mid-1890s (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - Informal portraits and snapshots, 1924-38, undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
      - Formal portraits, 1924-38, undated (Box 29, Folder 4)
      - With Mary Sabin, 1939-40, undated (Box 29, Folder 5)
      - Statue, bust, paintings, and drawings, undated (Box 29, Folder 6)
        [See also Memorabilia -Famous American Women From Portraits by Leon Gordon]
      - Group photographs
        - Awards and honors, 1933-51, undated (Box 29, Folder 7)
        - Signing Colorado Health Bill, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 8)
        - Miscellaneous, 1900-59, undated (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Sabin Family, 1944, undated (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Mary Sabin, 1891-1949 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Friends and associate, 1925-51, undated (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous, 1922-50, undated (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Memorabilia
    - Travel, 1929-41, undated (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Poetry, 1928-29, undated (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous, 1893-1954 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Women at Work, A Tour Among Careers, New York, 1939 (Box 31)
    - Retirement scrapbook, 1938 (Box 31)
    - Famous American Women from portraits by Leon Gordon, undated (Box 31)
    - Datebooks (22), 1938-52 (Box 32)
    - Address books (7), 1915, undated (Box 32)
    - Line-a-day diaries, (3) 1902-42, 1932 (Box 32)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - Elizabeth Blackwell Citation honoring the Work of Women in Medicine, New York University, 1953
  - Equal Rights (cover photo of Florence Sabin), January 4, 1930
  - Photograph portraits of Florence Sabin
    - G. Maillard Kesslere, 1936
    - G. Maillard Kesslere (2 views), 1938
    - Doris Jaeger, undated
  - William Henry Welch, 80th birthday, April 8, 1930, Memorial Continental Hall, Washington, D.C.